"一声尖叫破空而来
"A scream pierced the air,
却只传入了死者的耳中"
falling only on the deaf ears of the dead."
-你确定  -太夸张了吗
- Really? - A little too over the top?
我觉得你写太久了以至于
I think you've been writing too long
忘记"I在E前  除非是跟在C后面"[单词拼写记忆法]
not to know that it's "I" before "E" except after "C."
-没听说过"拼写检查"吗  -当然
- Ever heard of spell-check? - Yes, of course.
她有红色的头发  远远超出年龄的智慧
She's got red hair, she's wise beyond her years,
她还会告诉她老爸
and she's about to tell her dad what she thinks
他新书最新一章写的如何
of the latest chapter of his new book.
我喜欢这章  尤其是
I loved it, especially the part
妮基和洛克在航母里那段
with Nikki and Rook in the aircraft carrier.
太赞了
Awesome.
别说啦  人家会不好意思的
Stop it. You're embarrassing me.
不过  我确实有个小意见
I do have one note, though.
那个新的角色  抢劫案探长
This new character, the, uh, robbery detective...
斯莱明  这人如何
Schlemming. What about him?
这人看起来好像凭空冒出来的
Well, he seems like he kinda came up out of nowhere.
确实  这点我非常赞同
Yeah, well, I can't argue with that.
-他被描写地好像一个蠢蛋  -你也觉得吧
- He's coming off a bit like a doofus. - You think?
我觉得你应该删了他
I think you should lose him.
要真这么简单就好了
If only it was this easy.
谢谢你的帮助  宝贝儿
Thank you for your help, sweetie.
我的进度已经严重落后了
I am so behind on my deadline.
那是因为你总是找各种花样拖延时间
That's 'cause you always find new ways to procrastinate.
也可能是花样主动找我
Or they find me.
老妈  你好
Hello, mother.
孩子们好  我不能久留
Oh, hi, guys. I can't stay.
我只是来拿一条裙子
I'm just picking up a dress.
切特今晚要带我去剧院
Chet's taking me to the theater this evening.
你们去看什么剧
Oh, what are you seeing?
彼托夫斯基的新话剧《觉醒边缘》
New Petrofsky play, "Edge Of Awakening."
等一下  这部剧你不是还去试镜了吗
Wait a minute. Didn't you audition for that?
没错
Uh-huh, yes.
但那位出色的女演员玛吉·文思抢走了我的角色
And that wonderful actress Madge Vance got my part,
一如她之前所做的
the way she usually does.
她连你的朋友都算不上
Well, she's not even really your friend.
-你还去给她捧场  真好  -我知道
- It's nice that you go and support her. - I know.
而且我得赶紧去看  因为这剧快下线了
And... I have to go soon, because it's closing.
评论家对这剧的评价是"惨不忍睹"
The critics are saying it's a... "train wreck."
这才是我认识的玛莎·罗杰斯
Oh, there's the martha rodgers I know.
是贝克特
Ah, Beckett.
请告诉我又有谋杀案了
Please tell me there's been a murder,
不然我还得继续埋头写作
otherwise, I'll have to continue writing.
人们总说他们希望在睡梦中死去
People always say they want to die in their sleep.
是希望干脆利落地一枪了事
What you want is a good, clean shot to take you out
这样你才能死得痛快
before you know what hit you.
但这可怜的家伙
Not this poor guy.
子弹未击中心脏
Bullet missed the heart.
他过了很长一段时间才死掉
He didn't die for quite a while.
看上去他正伸手
Looks like he was reaching
去拿电话向人求助
for the phone to call for help.
直到凶手用那东西砸向他的头
Until our doer took that to his head.
可能凶手是怕
Probably didn't want to risk
邻居们听到第二声枪响
the neighbors hearing a second shot,
于是他随手抓起最近的东西
and so he grabbed the nearest thing
把他了结了
and finished him off.
闹钟上也沾上了血迹
There's blood spatter on the clock--
一定是在
must have been
袭击时从床头柜上掉下来的
knocked off the nightstand during the attack.
十点三十四分  至少我们知道了
10:34. At least we know what time
案发的时间
the festivities started.
没有强行闯入的痕迹
There's no signs of forced entry.
他很可能是故意把窗户打开  以便呼吸新鲜空气
He probably left this open so he could get a breath of fresh air.
而且也没有安全监控录像
And there's no security cameras either.
我进来的时候也没看到有监控
And I didn't see any on the way in.
清洁女工早上发现的尸体
Cleaning lady found him this morning.
她说  通常她来的时候
She said that usually, Wilder would've left for work
怀尔德已经上班去了
by the time she got here.
怀尔德  戴米恩·怀尔德吗
Wilder? Damian Wilder?
没错  你认识他
Yeah, you know him?
久仰其名
I know of him.
这是他产品的一个广告宣传照片
This is a photo from one of his ad campaigns.
他开的精品店专卖男士护肤用品系列
He--he runs a line of boutique men's skincare products.
你是说  浴室用品之类的
You mean, like, bathroom stuff?
他有一种爽肤水  完全不含酒精
He has got a toner, totally alcohol-free,
太神奇了
Fantastic.
他还有一种很不可思议的剃须膏
He's got a shaving cream that is ridiculous.
药店卖的东西已经足够我用了  兄弟
I'm good with the drug store stuff, man.
不不不  等一下
No, no, no, no, no. Hang on.
这玩意可以改变你的人生
This stuff will change your life.
-是热的  -热的
- It's hot. - It's hot.
-热的吗  -热的
- It's hot? - It's hot.
-真是热的耶  -他们怎么做到的
- It's hot. - How do they do that?
现代化学的神奇之处
Magic of modern chemistry.
这就好像在理发店刮胡子一样
It's like getting a shave from a barber.
实际上  这正是它的广告语  罐装理发师
Matter of fact, that's the tagline--barber in a can.
那一定很贵吧
So it's probably expensive, huh?
五十块一罐  但绝对物有所值
It's 50 bucks a pop, but it's so worth it.
-确实  -太值了
- Absolutely. - Totally.
兄弟们  别忘了这有个男人被杀了
Guys... A man has been murdered here.
我们就是在向他的遗产致敬呢
And we are... honoring his legacy.
简直就和《欲望都市》一样
It's like "Sex And The City,"
只不过是男人版的
only with boys.
也许你们可以找邻居们调查下
Maybe you guys can check in with the neighbors,
看他们有没有听到或者看到什么
see if they saw or heard anything?
好的  现在就去
Oh, yeah. All over it.
好  包我身上
Yeah, I'm on it.
来吧  卡塞尔  看看我发现了什么
Come on, Castle. Let me show you what I found.
这柜子里有东西被偷走了
Something was stolen from these cases.
那是湿度控制器
Those are humidity controls.
不管被偷的是什么  肯定很值钱
Well, whatever it was was very valuable,
因为凶手连等离子电视
because the killer passed up the plasma tv
和蓝光碟机都没拿走
and the blue-ray player.
抢劫被发现了吗
Robbery gone wrong?
看上去像是  是吧
Looks that way, doesn't it?
还有这个
And then there's this.
那是E还是O啊
Is that an "E" or an "O"?
"Murdero"  西班牙语里的谋杀吗
"Murdero," Is that spanish for murder?
或者是"Murdere"  凶手是法国人
"Murdere." The killer was French.
我怎么都想不通的是
The thing I don't get about it
为什么一个小偷要花时间
is why would a thief take the time
用死者的血留下信息呢
to write a message out of our vic's blood?
尤其是这种信息
Especially that message.
我是说  我们当然知道是谋杀
I mean, we know it's murder.
从尸体上就可以看出来了
The dead body's kind of a giveaway.
我们还在调查中
So we're still canvassing,
但我想你可能对这个消息感兴趣
but I thought you'd want to hear this--
一个邻居说
neighbor said
她昨晚正在跑步机上边跑边听音乐
she was on her treadmill last night listening to music.
所以她没听到枪声
So she didn't hear the shot.
没有  但她有把后门打开让猫进屋
No, but she did open her back door to let the cat in,
她看到有人从怀尔德的院子里出来
and she saw someone hopping over the fence
跳过院子里的栅栏
on their way out of Wilder's yard.
看到那人长相没
You get a description?
有  "一只脚在栅栏后消失不见了"
Yeah, "a foot disappearing over the fence."
知道时间吗
Did you get a time at all?
十点五十二分整
10:52 on the button.
她的报警器上还显示着呢
It was still on her alarm box.
她忘了在开门的时候关掉报警器
She forget she'd set it when she opened the door.
那么我们现在知道
So now we know what time
凶杀结束于昨晚十点五十二分
last night's festivities ended 10:52.
好了  让鉴证小组搜集一下指纹和纤维
All right, have CSU sweep for prints and fibers
确保他们把后院也搜索一遍
and make sure they hit the backyard as well.
好的
You got it.
戴明
Demming.
卡塞尔
Castle.
你们劫案组也用白板吧
You guys use, uh, boards down in robbery?
当然了
Sure, yeah.
明天再来参观吧
Well, come back tomorrow.
到时候这上面会写满有关谋杀的内容
It'll be full of all sorts of murder-y stuff.
贝克特让我来协助调查  所以
Beckett asked me to assist in the investigation, so...
是吗
Really?
是啊  因为案件有抢劫的成分
Yeah, because of the robbery component.
当然
Of course.
我查了一下怀尔德的亲属
I tracked down Wilder's next of kin,
他有个表哥叫布雷克
his cousin Blake.
他正在接待室里
He's in the interview lounge.
你知道他是怎么进入这行的吗
You know how he got in the business he did?
青春痘
Acne.
他青少年时期青春痘很严重
As a teenager, he had it something terrible.
当他向我借钱
When he asked me to
准备自己做生意的时候
lend him money to start up a business,
我很乐意借给他  他...
I was happy to do it. He...
他是个很优秀的人
He was one of the good ones.
我是说
I mean,
为什么会有人能做出这种事情来  我...
why somebody would do something like this, I...
布雷克
Blake,
我们希望你能帮我们搞清楚一件事
we were hoping that you could help us with something.
客厅里有一个陈列柜子
The display cases in the living room
柜子被打破了  里面的东西不见了
were broken into and their contents were missing.
那是他藏书的地方
Well, that's where he kept his books.
他是个收藏家  收集精印本书籍
He was a collector-- rare printings,
或是签过名的头版书  诸如此类
signed first editions, things like that.
那些书可能值好几千
Those could run into the thousands,
甚至值好几万美元
even tens of thousands.
这么说是劫杀了
So it was robbery?
有人为了那些书而杀了他
Somebody killed him to take his books?
也可能另有动机
Well, it's possible there's another motive.
我们在墙上发现了留言
We found a message written on the wall.
这就怪了
That's odd.
那方面我们还在查  我们请您来是希望您
We're still working on that. What we could really use
帮忙提供失窃书籍的相关信息
your help on is with the missing books.
他的藏品有目录吗
Did he have a catalog of his collection?
当然  戴米恩指望我
Sure. Damian looked to me
在生意上帮他一把
to help him out with the business side of things.
他的承保人是我的一个朋友
The insurer he used is a friend of mine.
-他一定有目录  -据我们所知
- He'll have a catalog.  - Well, as far as we know,
丢失的只有书籍
The only thing missing were the books, which suggests the
也就是说  凶手的目标很明确
perpetrator went there knowing what he was looking for.
他可能有机会去公寓踩过点
Could be he had an opportunity to case the apartment?
这么说来  那厨房
Well, the kitchen--
我是说  戴米恩重新装修了厨房
I mean, Damian had the entire thing renovated.
好几周公寓里都是装修工人
The place was crawling with workers for weeks.
因价值连城的失窃书籍而被杀
Killed for a fortune in stolen books.
我去问问装修工人  看有没有线索
So I'll run the work crews and see if anybody has priors.
谢谢  汤姆  谢谢你来帮忙
Thanks, Tom. I appreciate your help on this.
有消息我会通知你的
I'll let you know if anything turns up.
真不明白为什么大家都妄下结论
I'm not sure why everybody's jumping to the conclusion
认为这起谋杀是因为那些失窃的书
that this murder was about the stolen books.
也许因为它们失窃了
Maybe because they're missing.
镜子上的留言透露了明显的杀意
The message on the mirror suggests an intention to kill,
算是某种动机了
A motive of some kind.
偷书  只是顺手牵羊罢了
Stealing books-- just a crime of opportunity.
现在是谁在妄下结论了
And now who's jumping to conclusions?
我只是不想看到有人浪费时间
I just hate to see anybody waste their time.
这条留言才是关键  不是书
The key here is the message, not the books.
我觉得两条线索都该调查
I think we should pursue both lines of investigation.
好吧  反正他是你男友
Well, he's your boyfriend.
你说什么
Excuse me?
抱歉  我又妄下结论了吗
I'm sorry. Am I jumping to conclusions again?
与你无关
It's none of your business.
我查了查怀尔德的背景
Ran a background check on Wilder.
发现了这份他三天前
Found this incident report
提交给警方的事故报告
that he filed with the police three days ago.
有人蓄意破坏了他的公寓
Somebody vandalized his apartment.
门廊泼满红色油漆
Poured red paint all over his stoop.
没错  原来他的公司被一群
Yeah, it turns out that, uh, his company was being picketed
动物权益保护者围攻了
by animal rights protestors.
可他的产品都标注着"不含动物实验"啊
But all of his stuff is labeled "No Animal Testing."
问题在于他的一个
The problem was with, uh, one of his subcontractors,
承制产品的转包商
who was doing some of the manufacturing for him.
怀尔德毫不知情
Wilder didn't even know about it.
这就能解释留言内容了
That's what the message was.
不是拼错了  而是没写完
It wasn't misspelled. It was unfinished.
-他们是要写"凶手"  -所以你
- They were writing "Murderer." - So you think
认为是某个动物权益保护者杀了他
that one of the animal rights activists killed him.
当然  他们中的某人用够了假血
Sure. One of them had enough with the fake blood,
于是决定  "我要用真血留下信息"
decided, "I'm gonna send a message using the real thing."
也许我们该去怀尔德的办公室
Maybe we should pay Wilder's office a visit
弄清抗议的来龙去脉
and find out more about those protestors.
我们本想找另一家承制商
We were looking for another manufacturer
代替原来的那家
to replace the one we had been using.
但显然
But apparently,
我们没那些抗议者动作快
we weren't doing it fast enough for these protestors.
怀尔德先生想做正确的事
Mr. Wilder wanted to do the right thing.
真的  他只是还需要一点时间
He really did. He just needed a little more time.
周四晚  戴米恩公寓的泼油漆事件
The paint throwing incident at Damian's house
促使他做了决定
Thursday night was the last straw.
他原计划今早召开新闻发布会
He scheduled a press conference for this morning.
他未曾透露此事  但他准备
He hadn't told anybody, but he was planning to announce
为动物权益保护活动捐一大笔钱
a substantial donation to the animal rights movement
以表明公司诚信可鉴
as a sign of the company's good faith.
他们得偿所愿了
They got everything they wanted,
但他们还是杀了他
but they killed him anyway.
说句公道话  詹金斯女士
Well, to be fair, Ms. Jenkins,
关于这点  我们还不能肯定
we don't know that definitively.
周四的事故  是怀尔德先生第一次
The incident on Thursday, was that the first time
遭受人身攻击吗
that Mr. Wilder had been targeted personally?
他们通常只是在大楼外滋事
Usually, they just picket outside the building.
事态变得非常糟糕
It got so bad,
有一阵子  我们还动用了私人保安公司
we actually hired a private security firm for a while
以妨恐吓邮件内容成真
to run down some of the threats we got in the mail.
我们能看看他们发来的信息吗
Is there a chance we could take a look
可能会有帮助
at the information they developed? It could be helpful.
当然
Of course. Yeah.
达芙妮会汇总好交给你们的
Daphne will put it together for you.
我们还需要一份怀尔德先生
We'll also need to see a copy of Mr. Wilder's date book
近几周的日程安排
for the last couple of weeks.
没问题  要什么都行
Absolutely. Anything you need.
给你  先生
Here you go, sir.
真不敢相信你居然要了试用品
I cannot believe that you asked for samples.
她说我们要啥都行的
She said anything we needed.
而且这不是给我自己的
Besides, it's not for me.
是给莱恩和埃斯波西托的
It's for Ryan and Esposito.
你是指夏洛特和米兰达吧
Don't you mean Charlotte and Miranda?
等等  那我成了凯莉了
Wait a minute. That would make me Carrie.
你还真是都市型男啊  居然知道《欲望都市》
You're so metrosexual for even knowing that.
我只是在我妈看这剧的时候
I only watched that show out of the corner of my eye
稍微瞄了几眼
when my mother had it on.
真是越描越黑
That so did not come out right.
根据私人保安公司的记录
According to these notes from the private security firm,
这些人大多数很普通  都是些
most of these folks seem like average, everyday,
爱护环境的素食主义者
tree-hugging vegetarians.
目前为止  他们做过最糟的事
I mean, so far, the worst any of them has done
就是闯进一家实验室放跑了一堆老鼠
is break into a lab to free a bunch of mice.
你那边有什么发现吗
You come up with anything?
怀尔德的日程表里
There are a handful of recent entries
有好几条是要见一个叫娜塔莎的人
in Wilder's calendar for someone named Natasha.
可能是他刚交上的女友
Could be someone that he started dating?
我查了装修过被害人厨房的工人
So I ran the workmen who renovated your vic's kitchen.
有一个人值得注意
And one of 'em popped.
他叫杰克·凯布里斯
Meet Jake Cabrese.
他去年工作过的两所公寓
Two of the apartments
随后都遭到了抢劫
he worked on in the past year were later robbed.
两件案子他都有嫌疑
He was a person of interest in both investigations,
但最终罪名都没成立
but neither of them made.
看来我们得找他谈谈
Sounds like someone we should talk to.
我们说话这会儿  已经有警员在查他的下落了
Well, we're running down his whereabouts as we speak.
啊哈  看看这个兰斯·纽曼
Aha! Meet Lance Newman--
因暴力滋事被捕过五次
Arrested five times for violent agitation.
他最爱的抗议工具是...假血
His favorite tool of protest-- the bucket of fake blood.
这种抗议活动不都爱用假血吗
Isn't fake blood kind of a staple with these types?
上个月
Last month,
他在一名国会议员的车上喷上了"凶手"
he painted the word "Murderer" on a congressman's
因为对方投票反对禁渔期
car because he voted against a fishing ban.
当司机试图阻止时  他用油漆桶
When the driver tried to stop him, Newman bashed him
重重击打了对方的头部
in the side of the head with his paint bucket.
要是能找到线索  把他和受害人联系起来
You know, I'd like him more if we could find something
我会觉得他嫌疑更大
that would connect him with our vic.
你是说  写给怀尔德的一堆恐吓信吗
You mean like the string of violent letters he wrote
直接寄到他家的
to Wilder... sent to his home address?
干得好  卡塞尔  咱们去抓他吧
Nice job, Castle. Let's go pick him up.
好啊  咱们走
Yeah. Let's.
你们抓错人了
You've got the wrong guy.
上周四晚
Last thursday night,
有人在怀尔德家门廊倒满了假血
someone pours fake blood all over Wilder's stoop.
三天后  他便死于非命
Three days later, he ends up dead.
稍有头脑的人  都会把这两件事联系起来
It does not take a genius to make the connection.
没错  可我没杀他
Yeah, but I didn't kill him.
听着  我已经告诉你了
Look, I-I told you already.
周日晚我去看电影了
I went to the movies Sunday night.
没错  我们派人去核实那个不在场证明了
Yes, yes, yes. We have someone running down that alibi.
那周四呢  还有不在场证明吗
What about Thursday? You got one for then, too?
周四...我不记得了
Thursday... I don't remember.
好吧  那你去拘留所过一夜怎么样
Well, then how about you spend the night in lockup?
可能会帮你想起些什么
Might refresh your memory.
上周四  我带着油漆去了他家
Last thursday, I went over there with the paint--
中了  所以你承认
Bam! So you admit that it was you
-是你破坏了怀尔德的公寓  -卡塞尔
- who vandalized Wilder's apartment? - Castle.
是  没错  我往他家门廊泼了油漆
Yes. Okay. I-I threw paint on his stoop,
也就是那时  我听到
which is then when I heard him
他在屋里和人争吵  是个女人
fighting with someone inside, a woman.
他们互相砸东西
They were throwing stuff,
我真以为他们会杀了对方
and I really thought they were gonna kill each other.
你看到她是谁了吗
Did you see who she was?
没有  我只听到他们大喊大叫
No. I just heard them yelling.
你具体听到些什么
And what exactly did you overhear?
她说什么被羞辱了
She said something about being humiliated,
而他说到了枪
and he said something about a gun.
枪
A gun?
"你拿枪指着我脑袋"  我想是这句
"You put a gun to my head," I think it was.
好吧  现在你开始瞎编了
Okay, now you're just making stuff up.
纽曼先生  很幸运
Well, Mr. Newman, good thing you used
周日晚你使用了影院的自动售票机
the automated ticket booth at the theater Sunday night.
你的不在场证明被证实了
Your alibi checked out.
-真的  -真的
- Really?  - Really?
真的
Really.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
看看这个  根据他的日程表
Check this out. According to his calendar,
怀尔德周四晚跟这个娜塔莎一起用了餐
Wilder had dinner with this Natasha person Thursday night.
她会不会就是我们那位
Could be that she's the person
爱护动物的朋友说到的那个人
our animal-loving friend was talking about?
你不是说那是他编造出来的吗
I thought you said that he was making all that up.
-那是  -刚刚和怀尔德的助理通过电话
- That was-- - That was Wilder's assistant on the phone.
显然
Apparently...
怀尔德和娜塔莎·派珀最近刚开始约会
Wilder and Natasha Piper had started dating recently.
-平面广告上那个女孩吗  -是的
- The girl from the print ads? - Yep.
助理说她是个相当难相处的人
And she said she was a real piece of work.
几周前大闹拍摄现场
Tore up a set at a photo shoot a couple of weeks ago
仅仅是因为别人给她拿错了瓶装水
because they had the wrong bottled water for her.
那看起来她很有可能是周四晚
Well, it seems like a good bet she was the one
与怀尔德争吵的那位
fighting with wilder thursday night.
是啊  也可能是她周日
Yeah. Could be she went back on Sunday
把人杀掉的
to get one last word in.
明早就让她来警局
I should pick her up in the morning.
工人那面调查的怎么样了
Hey, how did things go with the workman?
在他的车库找到了他
Well, found him sitting in his garage
坐在价值几千元偷来的电动工具上  但是
on a couple of G's worth of stolen power tools, but...
案发当晚
The night of the murder, it turns out
他在教堂观看他的孩子表演
he was watching his kids in a play at church, so...
好吧  运气真的是太差了
Yeah, it's been that kind of a day.
-是啊  准备走吗  -是的
- Yeah. You ready to go? - Ready.
今晚不是收工了吗
Thought we were knocking it off for the night.
是啊  我们只是合乘出租车
We are. We're just, um, sharing a cab.
晚安  卡塞尔
Night, Castle.
-晚安  -晚安
- Night. - Night.
那部剧怎么样
Hey. How was the play?
糟透了
Oh, awful.
那你一定很高兴吧
Well, that must've made you happy.
知道最糟的是什么吗
You know what the worst part was?
这部剧本身的低劣把玛吉的
It's badness made Madge's performance
演技显得很高超
all that much better.
她很棒
She was wonderful.
她就像是...启示录一般
She was... like a revelation.
真是抱歉  母亲
Oh, mother. I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
知道吗  进剧场的时候我还在想
You know, I went into the theater thinking,
她是从我手上把那个角色偷走的
yeah, she kinda snaked that part out from under me.
但是我却不得不承认
But then I... I hate to admit it.
她得到那个角色当之无愧
She deserved to get it.
我确定你演那个角色也会很出色的
I'm sure you would've been terrific in that role.
你真是太贴心了
Aw, you are so sweet.
知道吗  亲爱的
But you know something, darling?
人这一生中  你要接受不是每件事都
In life, you just have to accept the fact
顺你心意这个事实
that not everything is gonna go your way.
感谢你能赶来  派珀小姐
Thank you so much for coming in, Ms. Piper.
首先  对你男友的去世我深感惋惜
First of all, let me say that I am so sorry for your loss.
别  还是算了
Yeah. Don't be.
你们两个约会多长时间了
Uh, how long had the two of you been seeing each other?
不记得了  两个月?  这很重要吗
I don't know. Two months? Does it really matter?
显然不重要
Apparently not.
要我说  他死有应得
If you ask me, he got exactly what he deserved.
是吗
Really?
是啊
Yeah. Really.
胸部中枪
Bullet in the chest.
别忘了他还被重击的那部分
Don't forget about the bludgeoning part.
怎么会忘呢  就在他那小脑瓜上
Oh, how could I? Right upside his little head.
你为什么这么做
So why did you do it?
你真的认为是我干的吗
You seriously think I did this?
我在报纸上读到的  但是他那是自找的
I read about it in the paper, but he did have it coming.
你能相信那个臭小子
Can you believe that that little toad
竟然对我不忠吗  对我?
was cheating on me? Me?
好吧  让我们从头开始说起
Okay, so why don't we just start from the beginning?
他被害的那天晚上你在哪
Where were you the night that he was killed?
周日我在汉普顿
On Sunday, I was in the Hamptons.
早上坐随停巴士去的
I took the jitney out in the morning
偏偏又和佩里斯·希尔顿[八卦博客写手]坐在一起
and sat next to Perez Hilton of all people.
他都写到博客里了
He blogged all about it.
你可以自己看看去
You can check yourself.
有位证人说
Well, we have a witness
周四那天在怀尔德先生的公寓  有个女人
who says that Mr. Wilder argued with a woman
和他发生了争吵  那人是你吗
in his apartment on Thursday. Was that you?
不  不是我
No, that wasn't me.
很可能是他和"她"在一起
So it probably means that he was with her.
那个和他偷情的贱人
The bitch that he was two-timing me with,
汽车旅馆那个
the one from the motel.
-哪个汽车旅馆  -他的确写到博客了
- What motel? - Ah, he did blog about it.
你们在南汉普顿烧烤店吃饭了
You two ate at the Southampton Grill?
-我喜欢那个地方  -卡塞尔
- I love that place. - Castle.
哪个汽车旅馆
What motel?
新泽西的一家  我周四早上跟踪到的
The one in Jersey that I followed him to Thursday morning.
我是对的  他的确出轨了
I was right. He was cheating on me.
-和谁  -我不知道
- With who? - I don't know.
他去了二楼角落的那个房间
He went up to the corner room on the second floor.
我可没待在那看戏
I didn't stick around to watch.
这么说你不确定
So you can't be sure
和他见面的人是个女人
that it was a woman that he was meeting with.
是的  但是他去那还能干什么
No, but why else would he be there?
我还要说  她肯定
And just for the record, she's gotta be
是个不入流的货色  因为那地方糟透了
some kind of dirty skank, 'cause that place was a dump.
不入流的货色  在一家破烂的旅馆
A cheap skank... at a rundown motel
这个线索比生气的前女友要好很多
is actually a better lead than an angry ex-girlfriend.
比失窃的书好更多
And a much better lead than stolen books.
说什么呢
What was that?
我说...天啊  小伙子们
I said... my, don't you gentlemen
-胡子刮得很干净啊  -是啊  东西不错
- look clean-shaven today? - Yeah, sweet stuff, bro.
珍妮说我的脸从没这么光滑
Yeah, Jenny said my face never felt so smooth.
罐装理发师
Barber in a can.
好了  伙计们  了解了
Okay, guys. Got it.
挤出来是热的  办案呢
Comes out hot. Case?
好的  怀尔德的财产情况没有异常
Oh, yeah, uh, nothing unusual in Wilder's financials.
通话记录也很正常
His call records were clean, too.
没有意料之外的通话
No calls except to places you would expect.
弹道检验没有查出什么
Ballistics report came back negative.
公寓和后院都没有
No unusual fibers or fingerprints
异常的纤维和指纹
in the apartment or backyard either.
好吧  再去询问一遍邻居
All right, talk to the neighbors again.
找找有没有人周四晚上看到他和
Find out if any of them remember seeing him
一个女人在一起
with a woman thursday night.
我在想一个像怀尔德这样的有钱人  为什么
I'm wondering why a man as wealthy as Wilder
会选择新泽西的便宜旅馆和人幽会
would choose a cheap motel in Jersey to have a tryst.
也许不单单是幽会
Maybe there's more going on than just a tryst.
他的名字叫做戴米恩·怀尔德
His name is Damian Wilder.
从未见过他  不过那天不是我当班
Never seen him before. But I wasn't on duty.
是本尼当班
Benny was.
我想和本尼谈谈
Well, I'd like to talk with Benny.
我也想  他今天没来上班
So would I. He didn't show up for work today,
所以我才在休息日来上班
Which is why I'm here covering on my day off.
你有他的联系方式吗
Do you have contact info for him?
二楼那个角落的房间
The corner room, second floor,
上周四谁住在那
who stayed in there last Thursday?
我看看  提前支付的现金  租了四天
Oh, let's see. Paid cash up front, four nights.
名字是  斯嘉丽·奥哈拉[《乱世佳人》女主角]
Name was... Scarlett O'Hara.
斯嘉丽·奥哈拉
Scarlett O'Hara?
她是小说里的人物
She's... a fictional character.
这地方没人留真名
It's that kind of place.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
本尼的室友说他下班回来  装个一个包
Benny's roommate said that he came home from his shift,
匆忙离开了
packed a bag and left in a hurry.
时机看起来是不是有点可疑呢
Is it just me, or is the timing a little suspicious?
我在系统里发一份他的通缉令
I'm gonna put a want out for him in the system.
他肯定在什么地方
He's gotta be out there somewhere.
那位员工说
You know, the clerk said
那房间  神秘女子租了四天
our mystery woman rented the room for four nights.
怀尔德的日程排的相当满
Wilder's calendar was pretty packed the whole time.
很难想象他有时间去见她
It's hard to figure him getting back out there to see her.
那她为什么租那么长时间
So why did she rent it for that long?
那到底是什么状况
What was going on out there?
重大新闻
Breaking news.
猜猜什么东西刚刚在网上拍卖了
Guess what just turned up for sale online?
《麦田守望者》的第一版
A first edition "Catcher In The Rye"
和《战地钟声》的签名版
and a signed "For Whom The Bell Tolls."
我想这两本都是怀尔德的收藏
I take it those are both items in Wilder's collection.
正确  网站属于一位珍藏本经营商
Bingo. The site belonged to a rare book dealer.
名字叫卢卡斯·坎比  他有贩卖偷窃
Goes by the name of Lukas Canby. He's got a jacket
物品的案底  上个月在拍卖会上
for dealing in stolen property and last month,
他因暴力伤害另一位书商而被捕
he was arrested for assaulting another book dealer
起因是人家管了他的闲事
at an auction that didn't go his way.
这么说他有暴力前科
So he's got a history of violence
手里有死者的财产
and possession of our vic's property.
你想观摩  我让他就怀尔德谋杀一案
You care to sit in while I get him to confess
招供的过程吗
to Wilder's murder?
我很乐意
Don't mind if I do.
你想观摩
You care to sit in
我让他就怀尔德谋杀一案招供的过程吗
while I get him to confess to Wilder's murder?
价值五万美元的书
$50,000 worth of books
是在一个死人家里丢失的
goes missing from a dead man's apartment,
书跑到了你的手里
turns up in your possession.
你能看出问题所在吧  卢卡斯
You can see how that's a problem, can't you, Lukas?
-你想解释一下吗  -当然
- You want to explain what happened? - Sure.
不过你们不会相信我的
But you'll never believe me.
你试试
Try us.
我从公园一个家伙手里买的
I bought 'em from some guy in the park.
公园里?
In the park?
靠近七十六街的入园口
Near the 76th street entrance.
一个流浪汉摆在毯子上卖
This homeless looking guy had 'em laid out on a blanket.
他根本不知道值多少钱
Didn't have a clue what they were worth.
我用一百元就买下了所有书
Gave him 100 bucks for the whole lot.
那天我真是感觉很幸运
Man, was I feeling lucky that day.
跟着小妖精找到黄金的时候
Yeah, that's how I felt when I followed that leprechaun
我也是这么感觉的
to his pot of gold.
我没有偷那些书
I didn't steal those books,
我也绝对没有杀人
and I most certainly didn't kill anybody.
-是那个流浪汉  一定是  -真的
- It was this homeless guy. Had to be. - Really?
-是的  -你想让我们
- Yeah. - You expect us to
相信他闯进怀尔德的公寓
believe that he broke in to Wilder's apartment,
为了价值五万美金的书杀了他
killed him for $50,000 worth of books
然后以一百美金卖给你
just to sell it to you for 100 bucks?
这不合理  老兄
Doesn't add up, pal.
你周日晚上在哪里
Where were you Sunday night?
在家  独自一人
Home... alone.
我不会担心  你在监狱里不会孤单的
Well, I wouldn't worry. You won't be alone in your cell.
里克尔斯[纽约监狱]最近人满为患
Rikers is overcrowded these days.
让鉴证组去卢卡斯
Let's have C.S.U.
公寓和办公室提取样本
take samples from Lukas' apartment and office,
再与他们发现的样本对比
run them against what they recovered.
也许能发现他身处犯罪现场的证据
Might be something that puts him at the crime scene, yeah.
同时我们也该查查
In the meantime, we should check on his story
他说的那个流浪汉  以防万一
about the homeless guy, just in case.
今天天气不错  正好去公园
It's a nice day to be out in the park.
给你买个热狗吗
Can I buy you a hot dog?
他们应该去找那个流浪汉
They're supposed to be finding that homeless guy.
但他们互送秋波
I don't know how they're gonna do that
还怎么工作呢
when all they can do is make goo-goo eyes at each other.
贝克特是个好警察
Beckett's a good cop.
她可以一边查案一边暗送秋波
She can canvass and make goo-goo eyes at the same time.
也许我们应该致电旅馆  看看本尼是否现身
Maybe we should call the motel, see if Benny's turned up.
我十分钟前刚打过  另外有可能是
I just called ten minutes ago. Besides, chances are,
戴明抓的那书贩子干的
this book guy that Demming's got in the lockup did it.
别这样说
Oh, don't say that.
什么
What? Oh.
你想成为破案的功臣  而不是戴明
You want to be the one to crack it, not Demming, right?
那家伙甚至不是凶案组的
Well, the guy is not even homicide.
这难道不让你有点恼火吗
Doesn't that bug you just a little?
也许有点
Maybe a little.
但那不是你恼火的原因
But that's not why it bugs you, is it?
刚从电讯公司得到的消息
Just heard back from the phone company.
斯嘉丽·奥哈拉入住那家旅馆房间的四天里
Only one call came into the motel room
只有一个电话打进去
during the four days that it was rented to Scarlett O'Hara.
让我猜猜  白瑞德[《乱世佳人》男主角]  是吗
Ooh, let me guess. Rhett Butler, right?
白瑞德  了解笑点了吗
Rhett butler? See what I did there?
通话时长两分钟  就在怀尔德旧情人说
Call lasted two minutes. Came in around the same time
他进房的那个时间打的
that Wilder's ex said he went up to the room.
唯一知道怀尔德在那里的人
Well, the only one who would've known Wilder was there
肯定是和他幽会的那个女人
would've been the woman planning to meet him.
也许她打来说她迟到了
Maybe she called to say she was running late.
是啊  接下来才是重点
Yeah, well, here's the money part...
这电话来自怀尔德的公司
The call came from Wilder's company.
他和公司同事有染
He was having an affair with someone from work.
是的  但很不幸  他们追查到的电话
Yeah, but unfortunately, the way that they route the calls,
我们只能把范围缩小到
we were only able to narrow it down to an extension
公司三楼的一个分机
on the third floor of his building.
我们可以排除男士
Well, and we can rule out all the men,
因为我们知道斯嘉丽是个女的
since we know Scarlett was a woman.
没错  最有可能的是
Yeah, and most likely, it was the woman
这女人是和怀尔德在公寓里吵架的那个
that Wilder was fighting with at his apartment.
肯定有方法可以找出她是谁
There's gotta be a way we can figure out who it was.
我们可以进行声音辨认
We could do a sound lineup.
声音辨认
Sound lineup?
我们叫偷听吵架的那家伙
Yeah, we bring in the guy who overheard the argument,
听听三楼所有女士的声音样本
have him listen to voice samples from all the women
看看他能不能认出那个声音
on the third floor, see if he recognizes any of 'em.
可以吗
You can do that?
我们甚至不需要叫那些女士来
We don't even need to bring any of the women in.
可以进入语音留言系统
We can patch into the voice mail system,
提取样本
pull samples from there.
伙计们  如果成功的话
You guys, if this works,
-你们俩一年的剃须膏我包了  -成交
- I'll keep you both in shave cream for a year.  - Deal.
你们找到他了
You found him?
坐下
Take a seat.
是的  运气不错  显然马蒂是个瘾君子
Yeah, we got lucky. Apparently, Marty the junkie here,
公园的那个地区是他的据点
is a permanent fixture in that part of the park.
他就在卢卡斯买书
He was panhandling right about
那地方行乞
where Lukas said he bought the books.
而且马蒂承认以一百美金
Which Marty's already admitted to
把书卖给了他
selling to him for 100 bucks.
那他承认入室抢劫怀尔德的公寓了吗
Has he admitted to breaking into Wilder's apartment?
接下来就很有趣了
Well, that's where things get interesting.
他入室抢劫的不在场证明成立
His alibi for the break-in is solid.
他在一家救助站做了几小时清洁工
He picked up a few extra bucks at a soup kitchen,
赚点外快
cleaning up after hours.
他说是在垃圾桶捡到的那些书
Claims he found the books in a garbage can.
还说看见是有人扔在那里的
Says he saw somebody dumping them there
就在凶案发生的几小时后
a couple hours after our murder.
那人肯定就是凶手
Which, pretty good bet, that is our killer.
我要带他去做凶手人像素描
I'm gonna sit him down with a sketch artist now.
走吧  马蒂
Come on, Marty.
神秘女人那里有线索吗
Any leads on our mystery woman?
事实上有
Actually, yes.
这是凯蒂·马克斯
Hey, you've reached Katie Marks.
我现在不在座位上
I'm not at my desk right now.
请留言  我会尽快回复
Leave a message, and I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
-不是她  -好吧  下一个
- That's not her.  - Okay. I will cue to the next one.
瘾君子马蒂说他正好看到
So did Marty the junkie say he got a good look
-扔书那人样子 -没错  是的
- at who it was that tossed the books?  - Pretty good, yeah.
希望两条线索有一个会有突破
Hopefully, one of these two leads will pan out.
-希望是  -我去看看那个素描图
- Yeah, hopefully.  - I'm gonna go and check on that sketch.
留言或打我手机
Leave a message or try my cell.
好的  这个呢
Okay, how about this one?
嗨  我是简
Hi, this is Jane.
我不在座位上  请留言
I'm away from my desk, so please leave a message.
-不是吗  -我是苏菲
- No dice, huh?  - You've reached Sophie.
我现在不能接听你的来电
I can't take your call right now,
请留下你的名字和电话  我会回复你
so leave your name and number and I'll get back to you.
下一个
Next one.
还剩3个
Only three more.
嗨  我是丽莎·詹金斯
Hi, this is Lisa Jenkins.
如果你听到这个  说明我不在办公室
If you've reached this, that means I'm out of the office.
-请留言  -就是她
- Please leave a message.  - That's her.
丽莎·詹金斯  就是我们询问的那个
Lisa Jenkins? That's the woman we interviewed.
你确定吗
You sure?
是的  很肯定
Yeah, I'm positive.
记住我们的交易  卡塞尔
Remember our deal, Castle.
是丽莎·詹金斯
It was Lisa Jenkins.
怀尔德当时和丽莎吵架...
Wilder was fighting with Lisa..
-非常有可能  -是的
- That's a pretty solid likeness.  - Yeah, right?
什么
What?
这是马蒂看到扔书男子的素描
It's Marty's sketch of the man he saw tossing the books.
怀尔德的表哥  布雷克
Wilder's cousin--Blake.
我们有一个证人听到丽莎·詹金斯
So we have a witness who says that he heard Lisa Jenkins
和怀尔德大吵一架
in a knock-down-drag-out with Wilder,
还有一个证人说
and another one says
看到怀尔德的表哥扔书
that he saw Wilder's cousin dumping his books.
但我们没查到两位嫌疑人的杀人动机
But what we don't have from either suspect is motive.
简单  丽莎和怀尔德奸情出现了问题
Easy. Lisa's affair with Wilder went south.
他们不可能再一起共事
They could no longer work together side by side,
但她却不想被迫辞去工作
and she didn't want to have to quit her job.
-戴明探长  -什么都有可能
- Detective Demming?  - Oh, it could be anything.
我不知道  也许布雷克不愿意看到
I don't know. Maybe Blake didn't like the fact
怀尔德比他更成功的事实
that wilder grew up to be more successful than him.
也许他已经厌倦了高尔夫总也打不赢
Maybe he was sick of getting beat at golf.
-高尔夫  真的吗  -老实说
- Golf, really?  - To be honest with you,
我现在不关心动机这事
I'm not that concerned about a motive right now.
我有目击证人在案发当晚看到
I've got an eyewitness that saw him tossing his cousin's
他在扔他表弟价值不菲的书籍收藏
prize book collection the night of the murder.
我也有证人
I have a witness,too.
听到怀尔德三天前和某人吵架
That heard Wilder fight with someone three days ago.
-这毫无意义  -伙计们
- It doesn't mean anything.  - Guys--
至少有杀人动机
At least I have a motive.
是的  但不足以证明嫌疑人在案发现场
Yeah, but can't put your suspect at the scene.
-伙计们  -你有说过找到杀人动机吗
- Guys--  - Did I miss the part where you had a motive?
你不需要杀人动机
You don't need a motive.
伙计们  这不是比赛
Guys. This isn't a competition.
我们找到两个嫌疑很大的嫌犯
We've got two good suspects.
我觉得应该把他们都带来问话
Seems to me that we should bring them in
听听他们的说辞
and see what they say.
好吧  好吧
Okay, fine.
戴米恩和我周四晚上
Damian and I had an argument
在他的公寓里吵了一架
at his apartment on Thursday night.
但我和他没偷情
But I was not having an affair with him,
我从未去过新泽西的旅馆和他幽会
and I never went to New Jersey to meet him in any motel.
我们的证人说他听到扔东西的声音
Our witness said that he heard things being thrown,
还听到怀尔德说
and that Wilder said something
有枪指着他的头
about having a gun to his head.
不不不  他在说那些抗议者
No, no. He was talking about the protestors.
戴米恩因为我们找新承制商
You see, Damian was unhappy because it was taking
花费了很长时间而不高兴
so long for us to find a new manufacturer.
作为生产总监  他觉得错在我
And as head of production, he felt that was on me.
我觉得这不公平
I didn't think it was fair,
事情有点过火
and... things got a little heated.
能告诉我们你周日晚上在哪里吗
Could you tell us where you were sunday night?
我和一些朋友外出吃饭
I was out for dinner with some friends.
-晚餐后呢  -你能具体点吗
- After dinner?  - Can you be a little more specific?
好的  我可以更为具体
Yeah, I can be a lot more specific.
在10:34至10:52这段时间
Uh, let's say between 10:34 and 10:52.
我在家  独自一人
I was home... alone.
不过我出去了一会儿
Though I did step out at some point.
我住所附近路边停车是交替的
My neighborhood has alternate side of the street parking,
我必须开走我的车  再找停车位
and I had to move my car, find a different space.
有人看见你吗
Did anyone see you?
-这个我不知道  -那是几点
- Not that I know of.  - And what time was that?
也许是10:15
10:15 maybe?
你的住所离怀尔德
You live, what,
居住的莱克斯街有十个街区
ten blocks down Lex from where Wilder lived?
在那个时间  开车两分钟就可以到
At that hour, that drive would take you two minutes.
我想是
I suppose.
我从未算过时间
I've never really timed it.
当你问她周日晚上在哪的时候
Did you see how squirrelly she got
她表情很奇怪  你发现了吧
when you asked her where she was Sunday night?
我会叫埃斯波西托去盘问她的门卫
I'll have Esposito talk to her doorman.
也许有监控录像可以查出
There might be security cam footage that might nail down
她离开公寓多久
how long she was gone from her apartment.
我可以旁听吗
Can I sit in?
想得美
Yeah, right.
真不敢相信仅凭流浪汉的片言只语
I can't believe that you guys are dragging me down here
你们就把我拽来审问
on the word of some bum,
还控告我谋杀我表弟
and then accusing me of murdering my own cousin.
相信我
Well, believe me.
我们也想排除你的嫌疑
We'd like nothing more than to be able to rule you out.
容我复述一次  周日晚上你和朋友
So tell me again. You said you were meeting some friends
相约喝酒  对吧
for a drink sunday night?
没错  在麦克杜根酒吧  十一点过后
Yeah, a-at Mcdugan's, after 11:00.
-离你表弟那相距一个街区  -对
- That's about a block away from your cousin's place. - Yeah.
你还说会见朋友之前你一直
And you say you were at home until you went out
-待在家里  -是的
- to meet your friends? - Yes.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
因为我会查问你的门卫
Because I'm gonna talk to your doorman.
-我那没有门卫  -那就问你的邻居
- I-I don't have one. - Well, I'm gonna talk to your neighbors.
我会核查你的消费记录
I'm gonna check your credit card receipts.
如果你说谎了
If you weren't home when you say you were,
我会查出来的
I am gonna find out about it.
好了  我说  我并没有直奔酒吧
All right, all right, fine. I didn't go straight to the bar.
我先去报摊  买了几根烟  行了吧
I went to a newsstand. I bought some cigarettes, all right?
我的朋友以为我戒掉了
My friends think that I quit,
但有时还是难忍烟瘾发作
but every once in a while, I get a craving that I can't put off.
所以我去了自动柜员机  取了点现金
So I went to the ATM, I got some cash.
买了包烟  抽了几根  把剩余的扔掉
I bought a pack, smoked a few, threw the rest away.
那时是几点
What time was that?
-忘记了  -自动柜员机会有记录
- I don't remember. - Well, your ATM will.
你可以坐一会
You can take a seat.
失陪一下
Excuse us.
对  附近有一个报摊
Yeah, at a newsstand,
在莱克斯街和32号大街转角位置
corner of 32nd and Lex?
行  去吧  我等着
Yeah, yeah, go ahead. I'll hold.
她出现了  正在出门
Ah, there she is, leaving her building.
时间为晚上10:18
Well, the time stamp says 10:18.
那她有足够时间赶在10:34之前
Which would give her plenty of time to jump in her car
开车去到怀尔德那
and get down to Wilder's place by 10:34.
我们已知凶手在10:52离开犯罪现场
Well, we know that the killer left the crime scene at 10:52.
所以问题是  她什么时候回到家
So the question is, when did she get back?
好的  知道  谢谢
Yeah, got it. Thanks.
银行确认了布雷克曾在自动柜员机取款
So the bank confirmed Blake's ATM withdrawal.
时间呢
And?
晚上10:39
10:39 pm.
正好在行凶时间区之内
Right smack in the middle of our timeline.
所以凶手并不是他
So that means it wasn't him.
她回来了  我倒回一点
Here she is coming home. Let me just rewind a little bit.
是什么时间
And what does the time stamp say?
10:47
10:47.
也在行凶时间区之内  不可能
That's inside our timeline. That's impossible.
也不是她干的
It wasn't her either.
我很肯定的
I was so sure.
我也是
Tell me about it.
伙计们  现在很晚了
You know what, guys? It's late.
今天就到此结束吧
Why don't we just call it a night?
晚安
Night.
-我回来了  -欢迎回家
- Hey there. - Hi.
你干什么呢
What are you doing here?
切特要参加一个无聊的政治活动
Oh, Chet had one of his ghastly political functions.
我需要信纸写信  我正写给
I needed my stationery. I'm writing a note
玛吉以表达我对其精彩演出的赞赏
to Madge to tell her how brilliant her performance was.
别写
Oh, don't do that.
-为什么  -妈妈  她是你的死对头
- Why not? - Mother, she's your rival.
你应该打压她  而不是慰藉她
You should be crushing her, not giving her comfort.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Yes.
不
No.
替我向玛吉问好
Give Madge my best.
好极了  时间刚刚好
Oh, good. You're just in time.
我们在斯嘉丽·奥哈拉这条线索上有进展
Looks like we caught a break on our Scarlett O'Hara.
-你找到她了  -找到次要的证人
- You found her? - Found the next best thing--
登记她入住信息的旅馆店员
The clerk who checked her in to the motel.
警察在大西洋城
Police picked him up in Atlantic City
以妨碍治安罪逮捕了他
for charges of disorderly conduct.
早上好  醉猫
Morning, sunshine.
本尼  为什么匆忙要离开呢
Why'd you leave town in such a hurry, Benny?
自觉运气不错
I was feeling lucky.
想尽快赌上几手
Wanted to get to the craps table fast as I could.
-本尼  在那玩得开心吗  -当然
- Did you have a good time down there, Benny? - Dude.
我很感激你们在我的要求下
I appreciate you guys in the rejecting
驳回了当地警方的控告
with the police down there on my behest.
-因为我们需要跟你谈谈  -乐意效劳
- Well, we wanted to talk with you. - Well, I'm happy to help.
只是有一个请求  你们能小声点吗
One favor, though. Could you not talk so loud?
我头痛得要命
My head is killing me.
上周四  你当班的那天
Last thursday, you were on duty
有一位叫斯嘉丽·奥哈拉的女子入住了
when a Scarlett O'Hhara checked in.
是的  没错  我记得
Yeah. Yeah, I think I remember.
-她长什么样  -让我想上她那种
- What did she look like? - I woulda done her.
除此以外呢
Anything else?
她身形比较娇小
Um... she was small for her size.
你认得这个男人吗
Do you recognize this man?
认得  这男的简直就是神经病
Yeah. That guy's a total nut bar.
上周  应该是上周四吧
Last week--think it was Thursday, matter of fact--
他开着一辆漂亮的外国货来的
He pulls into the motel in a fancy foreign job.
然后直接走进了二楼的拐角客房
He goes straight up to the corner room on the second floor.
几分钟之后  他冲下来
Couple minutes later, he charges down,
开始问我和你们问的
starts asking me all the same questions
同样的问题
you were asking me.
谁租的房间  她长什么样子
Who rented the room, what did she look like?
他竟然不知道
He didn't know?
我也是这么说得
That's what I said.
我对他说  如果他不知道房间是谁租的
I told him, if he had to ask me whose room it was,
他就不该二话不说径直进去
he shouldn't be going in there in the first place.
他气冲冲的走了  上了车  扬长而去
He stomped off, got in his car. He left. Boom!
再没有见过他
Never saw him again.
将来也不会  他周日晚上被杀了
And you won't either. He was murdered sunday night.
他的态度有问题  被杀了也不奇怪
With that kinda attitude, this is not surprising.
如果我的答案让你满意的话
Well, if I've answered all your queries to your satisfaction,
我可以走了吗
am I free to go?
我想再多问一个问题
Just one more query if you don't mind.
据大西洋城的警察说  你因试图
According to the atlantic city police, you were arrested
在脱衣舞夜总会的钻石休闲室
in the diamond lounge of a strip club
烧死一位牛仔小丑而被捕
for trying to set a rodeo clown on fire.
那是一场误会
That was a misunderstanding and--
我想问的是  时薪九美元的的店员
My question is, how does a $9-an-hour hotel clerk
怎么付得起五百元一小时的贵宾室
pay for a $500-an-hour VIP lounge?
我赌骰子赢了
I won at craps.
我说过了  我的运气不错
Like I said, I was feeling lucky.
那可是戴米恩·怀尔德的包
That's a Damian Wilder bag.
-谁  -本案受害者
- Who? - That's the guy who was killed.
你从哪得来的
Where'd you get that?
本尼  从哪得来的
Where'd you get it, Benny?
-拜托小声点  -从哪得来的
- Um, please, just not so loud. - Where did you get it--
我在房间里找到的
I found it in the room.
斯嘉丽·奥哈拉的房间
Scarlett O'Hara's room?
第四天退房之后
After checkout on the fourth day,
我上去盘点  她没有退钥匙
I went up there on account of, she never returned the key.
房间就像没人住过
The room was like nobody'd even been there.
床铺整洁  浴巾还在架子上
The bed was made, towels were on the rack.
我草草地巡视了一遍
I gave it a quick once-over,
打算告诉清洁工不用收拾房间了
figured I'd tell housekeeping not to bother going in.
结果在床底找到这个包
I found the bag under the bed.
里面有什么
And what was in it?
有什么
What was in it?
里面有钱  很多钱
There was money... lots of it.
有多少
How much?
里面有七万五千美金
75 grand. There.
本尼  钱都花光了吗
Did you blow it all, Benny?
这三天是我人生中最快活的日子
It was the best three days of my life.
一个装满现金的行李包
A duffel bag full of cash,
一间匿名租下的客房  和愤怒的怀尔德
an anonymous hotel room and an angry Wilder--
-综上所述  只有一个结论  -勒索
- All of that adds up to only one thing. - Blackmail.
只有这个比较靠谱
It's the only scenario that makes sense.
勒索者联系并指示怀尔德
So the blackmailer contacts Wilder with instructions
于指定时间在旅店碰头
to meet at the motel at a certain time.
可能是要给他看看
Probably to show him proof of
她掌握的把柄
whatever it is she has against him.
但她不想身份被识穿
But she doesn't want him to know who she is
或者她是怀尔德公司里的职员
or that she works at his company.
于是她打电话到房间  提出要求
So she calls in to the room, makes her demands by phone.
他质问店员  想查出敲诈他的
He confronts the clerk, trying to figure out who it
幕后黑手
is that's extorting him.
之后某一时段
At some point in time,
怀尔德提着装满现金的行李包返回房间
Wilder returns to the room with the duffel bag full of cash,
按照指示把包放在床底
puts it under the bed as instructed.
只是本尼抢在勒索者之前
Only Benny makes off with the money
把钱拿走  匆匆离开了
before the blackmailer's had a chance to pick it up.
这让勒索者很生气
Making for one angry blackmailer.
生气到要杀人
Angry enough to kill.
不  不是她  兄弟  这位死人先生
No, not her either. Man, this dead guy had
有一大票美女员工啊
a lot of good-looking babes working for him.
没有一个是斯嘉丽·奥哈拉
Any of them our Scarlett O'Hara?
不是她  也不是她  但我想上她
Uh, not her... Or her, but I'd do her.
不是她  这个我可不想上
Not her, who I would not do.
不是她  我可能会上她
Not her. I would maybe do her.
找到了  是她
Hey, look. It's her.
你确定是这女人来租房的
You're sure this is the woman who rented the room?
没错
Yes.
瑞贝卡·斯特朗  她是公司的实验室研究员
Rebecca Strong. She's a lab tech at the company.
好一双残酷的眼睛
Oh, she's got cruel eyes.
我想她一定很享受看着怀尔德痛苦死去
I'll bet she enjoyed watching Wilder suffer.
她在说什么
What did she say?
"我到底在想什么  我不该插手的"
"What was I thinking? I should've stayed out of it."
她在哭诉  女生们都从
It's cry talk. There's not a girl alive who hasn't heard it
伤心欲绝的女性朋友那听过
from a sobbing, heartbroken girlfriend.
瑞贝卡  你不该插手什么事
What should you have stayed out of, Rebecca,
勒索吗
the blackmail?
你本想做正确的事
You tried to do the right thing?
那是怎么回事  你有帮凶吗
Well, who wouldn't listen? Did you have an accomplice?
-就我一个  -那到底发生了什么
- Was just me.  - Well, then what is this all about?
苯并化合物
Benzophyosopheme.
抱歉  我没听懂
I'm sorry. I didn't get that one.
苯并化合物
Benzophyosopheme.
那不是哭诉  听起来像是某种化合物
That's not cry talk. It sounds like a chemical compound.
你负责产品测试  对吗
You work in product testing, right?
他们在公司的一种产品里
Were they using benzophyosopheme
使用了苯并化合物吗
in a company product?
这样做会有什么问题吗
Is there some kind of problem with it?
和这个勒索有关吗
Is that what the blackmail was about?
你说过
So then when you said
你打算做正确的事
that you were trying to do the right thing,
-你向你的上级报告了吗  -有过
- Did you approach your superiors about the problem? - Yes.
-怀尔德采取行动了吗  -没有
- And did Wilder do anything about it?  - No.
他生产了一种成品
He came out with a product
-里面有苯并化合物  -是的
-that has benzophyosopheme in it anyway.  - Exactly.
有什么严重副作用吗
Well, how bad is this stuff?
长时间使用  会损伤毛细血管
It can cause capillary damage if you use it long enough.
你想到  既然他们不听你的
So then you figured, if they weren't gonna listen to you,
干嘛不借此获利
why not cash in on it?
所以威胁道  你将公布于众
And then you threatened to make it public
除非怀尔德给你七万五千美元
If Wilder didn't give you $75,000.
-是的  -你真是胆大妄为  瑞贝卡
- Yes. - Well, you were in over your head, Rebecca.
我明白  我只想一切回到正轨
I know, and I want to make things right if I can.
为时已晚
It's too late for that now.
如果我把钱还回来
I--what if I gave it back?
-你杀了人了  -钱原封未动
- You killed a man.  - I still have the money.
-钱原封未动  -我杀人了
- You still have the money?  - I killed a man?
-戴米恩·怀尔德  -怀尔德先生不是我杀的
- Damian Wilder. - I didn't kill Mr. Wilder.
-钱在你手上  -还在我从
- You have the money? - It's still
床底下拿出的那个行李包里面
in the duffel bag that I got from under the bed.
等等  是放在汽车旅馆里的钱
Wait. The money from the motel room?
七万五千美元
$75,000.
那本尼找到的钱
Well, then the money that Benny found...
来自哪里
Where did it come from?
七万五千美元
$75,000.
如她所说  就在她客厅的壁橱里
It was in her hall closet just like she said it'd be.
两份勒索款  我糊涂了
Two blackmail payoffs? I don't get it.
瑞贝卡一定是取钱时
Rebecca must have missed the second duffel bag
没有拿走床下第二个行李包
under the bed when she went to pick up the money.
所以本尼才会
Which is why Benny found it
之后找到了另一个
when he went back there later.
但我们详细调查过
Yeah, but we looked through Wilder's financials
怀尔德的财产情况
with a fine-tooth comb.
没有线索证明是
There was nothing in there to suggest that
他出了这笔钱
he pulled that kind of cash.
也很难想象他没有出钱
It's hard to imagine he had it just lying around.
如果怀尔德没付钱  后果是什么
What would happen if Wilder didn't pay the blackmailer?
那就会让产品损伤
Well, that would mean letting
毛细血管的事情曝光
the capillary damage issue go public.
如果他不在乎呢
What if he didn't care?
如果他打算做正确的选择
What if he wanted to do the right thing
召回这种产品  尽管意味着
and pull the product, even if it meant
巨大的财政损失和诉讼
a huge financial hit and possible litigation?
那么拥有公司股份的人
Then anyone with a financial stake in the company
就有阻止此事曝光的动机了
Would have incentive to keep that from happening.
万无一失的办法就是将怀尔德灭口
And the surest way to do that would be to kill Wilder
并付清勒索款
And pay off the blackmailer.
既然这位表哥借给了怀尔德公司的启动资金
So the cousin would have company stock worth a fortune
那他在公司里的股份不会是小数目
from when he lent Wilder the start-up money.
是的  但不是他干的
Yeah, but we know he didn't do it.
丽莎·詹金斯  是她将这种危险产品推向市场的
And then Lisa Jenkins could be looking at criminal liability
为防止东窗事发  她也有杀人动机
if it got out that she let a dangerous product go to market.
是的  但也不是她干的
Yeah, but we know she didn't do it either.
-事情到这就说不通了  -卡塞尔
- Well, something doesn't make sense here.  - Castle.
过来
Come here.
怎么了  伙计们
Hey. Uh, what's wrong, guys?
苯并化合物
Benzophyosopheme.
不  不会在剃须膏里吧
Oh, no. Not the shave cream.
是的  就在剃须膏里  瓶子上就写着
Yeah, in the shave cream. It says here right on the can.
那就是挤出来是热的原因
That's how they get it to come out hot.
还不如用汽油刮胡子呢  老兄
Might as well just be shaving with napalm, bro.
她说  长期使用才会有损害
Well, she said it only does damage long term.
你们才用过一次而已
You guys have only used it the one time.
我也刚用第一瓶
I'm still on my first can.
有可能搞个毛细血管永久损伤
Coulda ended up with irreversible capillary damage.
我只是
I was...
时间区有问题
The timeline's wrong.
就是  用这么短时间不会有事的
Exactly. There wasn't time to do any damage.
-不是  是说谋杀案  -你在说什么
- No, for the murder.  - What are you talking about?
她在说什么
What is she talking about?
-不清楚  -你去哪
- I don't know.  - Where you going?
怀尔德的公寓  我知道谁干的
Wilder's apartment. I know who did it.
我知道谁杀了他
I know who killed him.
-谁  -谁
- Who?  -Who?
我对戴米恩·怀尔德的胸口开了一枪
I just shot Damian Wilder in the chest,
他开始流血
and he's bleeding out.
屋子里很黑
It's dark.
但我依然可以蘸取一些血迹
But I still manage to sop up some of the blood
之后来到这里
and I head over here
开始写留言
to start writing the message,
暗示凶手是抗议者
implicating the protestors.
但用时比我想象的要长
But it takes longer than I thought it would because
因为我需要不断去取血液
I keep having to go back in order to get more blood.
然后突然间  我听到后面有声音
And then all of a sudden, I hear a noise out the back.
我停下来了  告诉自己
So I stop and I think to myself,
算了  最好赶紧离开
You know what? I better get the hell outta here.
等等  你忘记了击打的部分
Hold on. You're forgetting about the bludgeoning part.
我从前门出去了  把门锁上
I walk out the front door and I let it lock behind me.
我快速穿过马路  叫了出租车
I race across the street, I hail a cab,
这时是10:40
and it's about 10:40.
但现在  你忘了被偷的书
Yeah, but now you're forgetting about the stolen books.
外面的声音  你认为还有其他人
The noise outside. You're thinking there was someone else.
那个人绝对没想到
Someone who had no idea that
怀尔德已经被枪击了
Wilder had already been shot.
有人从后院进入了卧室
Someone who came in through the back into the bedroom,
在黑暗中  找到了一件重物
And in the dark, found a heavy object
-在床上对他猛击  -两名凶手
- and bludgeoned him in his bed.  - Two killers.
第二名凶手偷走了书籍
So it's the second killer who steals the books.
将那些书
And then getting those books
从陈列柜中拿出来
out of this display case.
几分钟后
Takes a few minutes,
他就走到屋外了
after which, it's out the door,
这时是10:52
and it's 10:52.
这就给了第一位凶手足够的时间回家
Giving the first killer more than enough time to get home,
她就可以被看见  比如说监视摄像头
where she can be seen by, let's say, a security camera.
第二名凶手就不会
And the second killer wouldn't appear to
被牵扯进去
be involved if he was,
比如说  开枪时他在买香烟
say, buying cigarettes when the gunshot went off.
丽莎和布雷克先后过来谋杀怀尔德
Lisa and Blake came here separately to kill Wilder,
通过这样
and by doing that,
他们碰巧给了彼此不在场证明
they both inadvertently alibied each other out.
他们清楚在怀尔德坦白一切之前
They both knew it was their only chance
这是唯一的机会了
to stop Wilder before he stepped forward.
他要举行的那个新闻发布会
The press conference he had called...
不是关于动物权利的
It was not about animal rights.
他要发布产品的召回声明
He was about to announce a product recall.
他们各自都决定不能让这一幕发生
And they each decided they couldn't let that happen.
他们一前一后杀了他  而且两人都付了勒索款
They both killed him, and they both paid the blackmailer.
这就意味着  他们都得短时间内
Which means they both had to raise a lot of money
筹集一大笔钱
in not a lot of time.
我们发现他们从银行户头
We found withdrawals from bank accounts,
货币市场基金  甚至是养老基金中取款
money market funds, even 401ks,
两个人取款加起来都为七万五千美金
All of it totaling $75,000 from each one of them.
他们没有掩盖痕迹   因为他们不认为
They didn't cover their tracks because they didn't think
有人会查到勒索款并去调查
anyone would get on to the blackmail and come looking.
原来布雷克欠下大笔债款
It turns out Blake was leveraged in debt up to his eyeballs.
如果公司的股票遭受打击
If the company stock had taken a hit,
-他的人生就天塌地陷了  -她呢
- The whole house of cards would've fallen.  - And her?
她不愿在牢狱中浪费青春
She didn't want to serve time.
尽管剃须膏存在着严重问题
She's the one who sat on initial reports
但她还是通过了最初的检测报告
that there were problems with the shaving cream.
可怜的怀尔德
Poor Wilder.
做出正确的抉择  却招来杀身之祸
Tried to do the right thing and gets himself killed.
卡塞尔和戴明一开始  就找对了目标
Castle and Demming were right about the two of them all along.
你也不错  让他们都有了捉拿嫌犯的满足感
Nice of you to give them both the satisfaction of taking down their suspect.
这是我力所能及的
Oh, well, it's the least I can do...
男人的虚荣心啊
Male vanity being what it is.
听着  谢谢...
So listen, thanks...
谢谢你的帮忙
Thanks for your help on this one.
同一个团队嘛
Oh, you know, same team.
回见了
Guess I'll see you around.
好
Yeah.
一起谋杀案  两名凶手
One murder, two killers.
那可不是天天见得到的
That's something you don't see every day.
绝对可以为记录大全添上一笔
Yeah. That's definitely another one for the record books.
看见贝克特了吗  我要祝贺她
You guys seen Beckett? I wanted to congratulate her.
是她解开谜团的
She's the one who cracked this one open.
我想她在后面处理起诉的事
I think she's in the back processing the charges.
多谢
Thanks.
都投进了
Make all day.
空心入网
Nothing but net, though.
卡塞尔
Castle.
你还在这里干什么
What are you still doing here?
马上就要走了
Hey. Just about to leave myself.
案子结的漂亮
Good job closing the case.
我们是个不错的团队
Yeah. Well, we make a good team.
是的  晚安
Yeah. Good night.
谢谢  晚安
Thanks. Night.